Michael Fearnley

Software Engineer

Contact

Address Rochester, NH, 03867

Phone 603-507-4273

E-mail mtfear@hotmail.com

Technical Skills

Typescript / Javascript Excellent React Very Good Angular Very Good **VueJS** Very Good <u>AWS</u> Average PHP **Average** Seauelize Very Good GraphQL Good NestJS Good

Soft Skills

Communication

Excellent
Leadership

Very Good
Problem Solving

Excellent
Project Management

Very Good
Empathy

Very Good

Full Stack Software Engineer with significant experience helping teams accomplish a common goal through collaborative problem solving. Works well with others to create custom software applications using a multitude of technologies for the best end user experience.

Experience

2020-02 - Software Engineer
Current The Atom Crown Roston

The Atom Group, Portsmouth, NH

- Create quality applications for Atom's clients using NodeJS, MySQL, Sequelize, GraphQL, Angular 8+, VueJS, NestJS, TypeORM, PHP, and Cake
- Discover client needs and architect software solutions to meet those needs
- Create and deploy AWS environments using Jenkins and Github actions
- Review code to maintain consistent quality and ease of future development

2019-05 - Teaching Assistant

UNH, Powered By Trilogy Education Services, Portsmouth, NH

- Taught over 100 students about web development skills including React, Node/Express, MySQL, and MongoDB
- Maintain and update Gitlab repository
- Supported classroom activities, tutoring, and reviewing students' code

2019-11 - **Web Developer** 2020-02

Adrenaline Agency, Portsmouth, NH

- Build custom full stack application for dozens of Adrenaline's clients using PHP, Symfony, Doctrine, and iQuery
- Converted client's requests into functioning software

2018-11 - **Material Handler** 2019-05 Sig Sauer, Portsmouth, NH

 Stage jobs with material needed to keep assembly lines achieving desired productivity goals

2018-01 - **Manager** 2018-10

JDK Enterprises, Shelby Twp, MI

- Implemented online collaborative scheduling system
- Scheduled jobs to meet contracted workload with 4+ construction companies

2016-07 - Pastor of Student Ministries

Stoney Creek Community Church, Washington, MI

 Recruit and lead team of 20+ volunteers for 3+ weekly Student Ministry events

2013-06 - Pastor of Student Minstries
2016-07 Hillside Weslevan Church Cole He

Hillside Wesleyan Church, Cole Harbour, NS, Canada

 Build and frain teams of 10+ volunteers for weekly Children and Student Ministry activities

Education

2018-12 - Full Stack Web Development

University of New Hampshire - Portsmouth, NH An intensive 24-week long course dedicated to designing and building web applications. Completed course with GPA: 4.0

2009-08 - **Bachelor of Arts** 2013-05

Kingswood University - Sussex, NB, Canada Graduated Summa Cum Laude - Presidential Leadership Corps